Zach Danz

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

MEET ZACH

I am a 29-year-old Front End Web Developer who spent six years living in Shanghai, China. I have a diverse range of skills which allows me to bring so much more to the table than just coding. I have a lifelong love of tech, languages, performance, and learning of all kinds. Currently based in the USA.

CODING PROJECTS

API Employee Directory

<u>See Live View</u> | <u>View on Github</u> An employee directory using API fetch request, and a navigable modal.

WebAPP Dashboard

<u>See Live View | View on Github</u> An interactive Web-App made with SVG, adjustable graphs and charts, and more.

Hangman Game App

<u>See Live View</u> | <u>View on Github</u> An in-browser phrase-guessing game made with JavaScript.

Interactive Photo Gallery

See Live View | View on Github

A photo gallery app implemented with a
Lightbox and searchable based on keywords.

See full portfolio at:

https://zachdanz.codes

LANGUAGES

- English Mother Tongue (C2)
- Mandarin Chinese Fluent (C1)
- Turkish Fluent (B2)

CONTACT

Mobile: +1 (469) 604 4986 Email: zachary.danz@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Social Media Manager

YouTube | Jan 2019 - Current

- Manage "Nurtaç Türkeli" YouTube page with over 50,000 followers
- Make informed decisions based on data and analytics analysis
- Mastery of social media tools to optimize views and engagement

Corporate Training Facilitator

Zmackworks Training Group | Jul 2017 - Aug 2019

- Facilitation of corporate training in Shanghai and around Asia
- Leading English and Chinese half and full day workshops
- Run programs promoting critical thinking and problem-solving skills
- Role-play training simulations focused on emotional intelligence
- Developed original materials for professional use

EDU Specialist and Performer

Jiliguala | June 2017 - Aug 2019

- One of the largest Tech Startups in China, with over 9 million users
- Helped develop curriculum, strategy and implementation from scratch
- Acted as main performer in Blues Clues like video series for children

Director of Research and Development

Zmack Global Theatre Group | Feb 2016 - Aug 2019

- Directed and oversaw all classes in Improv training center
- Organizer of multicultural events averaging 100 attendees

Head Localizer and Copywriter

Mutantbox | Sep 2016 - Sep 2017

- Responsible for Chinese-to-English localization
- Social Media Management and SEO-based copywriting

English Teacher / EDU Expert

Various around China | Jul 2013 - May 2016

- Executed lessons, wrote lesson plans, time management
- Regular workshops, creative marketing for centers, recruiting, and more

EDUCATION

Front End Web Developer Tech Degree

Team Treehouse | 2019 - 2020

MA Intercultural Communication

Shanghai Theatre Academy | 2016-2019

BA Theatre Arts

University of the Incarnate Word | 2009-2013